contracts can create other contracts and
合同可以创建其他合同，这在您需要的情况下很有用
it's useful in situations where you
deploy the same contract many times with
使用相同的投入多次部署相同的合同，也可以是
the same inputs and it can also be
useful when you want to manage many
当您想从一个合同管理多个合同时非常有用
contracts from a single contract so for
example let's say that you deployed the
假设您以相同的合同部署了100次不同的合同
same contract 100 times with different
parameters want me to keep track of all
参数要我跟踪您刚刚部署的所有合同是
the contract that you just deployed is
to store the addresses of the contract
将链式合同的地址存储在数据库中的另一种方法是
of chain in a database another way is to
have a contract that creates other
具有创建其他合同并存储以下地址的合同
contracts and store the addresses of
these contracts inside the contract that
这些合同在创建它们的合同中，所以我将向您展示两个
created them so I'll show you two
examples how to create a new contract
示例如何从另一个合同内部创建新合同以及如何
from inside another contract and how to
send either at the same time that new
首先创建新合同的同时发送，我们需要两个
contract is created first we need two
contracts a contract that's going to be
签订合同，该合同将被多次部署
deployed multiple times this contract
will represent a car so it's going to
将代表一辆汽车，因此它将存储模型和汽车所有者
store the model and the owner of the car
and we'll initialize these two state
然后我们将在其中一个中使用构造函数来初始化这两个状态变量
variables using a constructor in one of
the examples I'm going to show you how
我将向您展示如何将任何一个发送到此构造函数的示例，所以我
to send either to this constructor so I
declare the constructor as payable so
将构造函数声明为应付款，从而完成合同的代码
that completes the code for the contract
that's going to be deployed multiple
接下来将要多次部署
times next we'll create a contract
that's going to create the contract
这将创建高于此合同车工厂名称的合同
above name this contract car factory the
function create will take two parameters
函数创建将采用两个参数，即车主和车型
the owner and the model of the car that
we're going to pass to the car contract
我们将传递给汽车合同，并在
and to create a new contract inside the
contract you start of the keyword new
您以关键字new开头的合同，然后是
and then followed by the contract that
you want to create in this case we're
您要在这种情况下创建，我们将创建汽车合同，
going to create the car contract and
we'll pass the parameter model and owner
我们将参数模型和所有者传递给汽车合同的构造函数
to the constructor of the car contract
so this code here will create a new
因此此代码将创建一个新合同并调用
contract and call the constructor of the
car con
汽车模型参数传递手
passing in the parameters model hand
owner and if you want to assign a
所有者，如果您想为该合同分配变量，请先
variable to this contract you first
start with the type of the variable in
从变量的类型开始，在这种情况下，它将是car，我们将命名
this case it will be car and we'll name
the variable also car so this is how you
变量也为car，所以这是您在另一个内部创建新合同的方式
create a new contract inside another
contract by using the keyword new next
通过使用关键字“ new next”来签订合同，我将向您展示如何创建新的
I'm gonna show you how to create a new
contract and send ETA with it and we can
签订合同并随同发送ETA，我们可以将食客发送到此汽车合同，因为
send eater to this car contract since
its marked as payable first I'm gonna
首先将其标记为“付款”，我将复制此示例作为我们的起点
copy this example as our starting point
and we name this function as create and
我们将此函数命名为create并发送，输入将是相同的
send either the inputs will be the same
as the example above and for this
如上面的示例，在这个示例中，您将食者发送到此
example you'll send eater to this
function so we'll declare as payable now
函数，因此我们现在将如何将进餐者发送到餐厅的语法声明为应付款
the syntax for how to send eater to a
new contract is a little bit confusing
新合同有点让您感到困惑，您需要先将这辆新车包装在
you first wrap this new car in a
parenthesis like this and to send either
这样的括号，并发送给您，请调用top top value函数，然后
you call top top value function and
inside the parenthesis you pass in the
在括号内，您传递了要发送给的etre数量
amount of etre that you're gonna send to
this contract and for simplicity we'll
这份合同，为简单起见，我们稍后将使用消息转发所有这些消息
just forward all of later using messages
all value so this is the syntax for how
所有值，因此这是如何将进餐者发送到新合同的语法，以及
to send eater to a new contract and the
syntax might look a little confusing so
语法可能看起来有些混乱，所以我记得语法的方式就像
the way i remember the syntax is like
this let's say that a contract has a
假设合同具有将XYZ作为输入的功能，
function that takes in XYZ as input and
the way you can call the function is
调用该函数的方式就像这样，您可以将一个食者发送到
like this and you can send one eater to
this function by using top value
通过使用最高值后跟您所升的升量来实现此功能
followed by the amount of liter that you
want to send to this function now you
现在想发送到此功能，您可以想象，当一个新合同
can imagine that when a new contract is
created the constructor which is a
创建了一个称为特殊函数的构造函数，您可以
special function is called and you can
send one liter to the constructor of the
通过调用最高价将一公升水发送给合同的建设者
contract by calling the top value
function and the way you would call the
函数，调用构造函数的方式是
constructor is
by using the new keyword and notice that
通过使用new关键字，请注意我们刚到达的语法是
the syntax that we just arrived is
similar to the Ballad syntax above so
类似于上面的民谣语法，这就是我记得如何
that's how I remember the syntax for how
to send eater to a constructor I hope
将食者发送给构造函数，我希望这很有意义，这样可以完成
that made sense so that completes the
code for how to send eater to a new
我之前说过如何将食者发送到新合同的代码
contract now earlier I said that a
contract that creates another contract
在这里创建另一个这样的合同的合同在以下方面很有用
like this one here is useful in
situations such as when the contract
诸如当合同被多次部署时的情况
that is getting deployed multiple times
uses the same inputs and also when you
使用相同的输入，以及当您想跟踪所有合同时
want to keep track of all the contracts
that's been deployed so I'm gonna
已经部署好了，所以我要说明这两种情况
illustrate those two situation using
this contract let's say that the owner
这份合同让我们说，车主应该始终是地址
of the car should always be the address
that created the contract
创建了合同，所以在这里汽车合同应该总是
so here the car contract should always
belong to the car factory contract so
属于汽车工厂合同，因此对于我们传递的所有者参数
for the owner parameter we're passing
the address of the car factory and we'll
汽车工厂的地址，我们将删除所有者参数，因此现在当
remove the owner parameter so now when a
new car is created the owner of the car
新车被创建后，该车的所有者将永远是该车的工厂合同
will always be this car factory contract
so that's the example of how you would
这就是如何使用固定输入创建合同的示例
create a contract with fixed inputs
moving on I'm gonna show you example how
继续前进，我将向您展示示例如何使用此合同来跟踪
to use this contract to keep track of
the individual contracts that's been
已部署的各个合同，因此我们将创建一系列汽车
deployed so we'll create an array of car
contracts and name it cars and once the
合同并将其命名为汽车，一旦汽车合同创建完毕，您将存储
car contract is created you'll store an
array of clause and that's it so let's
子句数组就是这样，让我们​​现在部署这些合同，我将展示
now deploy these contracts and I'll show
you a demo of calling these two
您在这里演示了调用这两个功能的演示我有汽车厂
functions here I have the car factory
contract decoyed and we don't need to
合同被诱骗了，我们不需要部署此车合同，因为这辆车
deploy this car contract since this car
factory contract when we call the
工厂合同，当我们调用该函数创建时，它将部署
function create it will deploy the
car contract I'm going to create Toyota
汽车合同我要为丰田花冠和特斯拉制造网络卡车，所以当
Corolla and Tesla a cyber truck so when
we call the create function they
我们将其称为create函数，他们部署了汽车合同，但我们没有
deployed a car contract but we don't
need to remember the address of the car
由于地址已存储，因此需要记住汽车合同的地址
contract since the addresses are stored
in this contract and we can get the
在这份合同中，我们可以获得汽车合同的地址，但是
addresses of the car contract but
accessing the cars array the Toyota
访问汽车数组，丰田卡罗拉将存储在索引0中，我们
Corolla will be stored at index 0 and we
get the address of the contract back now
现在获取合同的地址，以检查车内的模型
to check that the model inside the car
contract is actually your Toyota Corolla
合同实际上是您的Toyota Corolla，我们所有人要做的就是复制此文件
what we all have to do is copy this
address and then get the car contract at
地址，然后在该地址获取汽车合同，该合同在Toyota中
the address and it is in the Toyota
Corolla and we can check that the second
卡罗拉，我们可以通过复制来检查第二辆车是否再次是网吧
car is a cyber truck again by copying
the address getting the car contract at
地址在该地址获取汽车合同，然后检查状态
the address and then checking the state
variable model which is equal to Tesla
等于特斯拉网络工作的可变模型，所以这就是您创建一个
cyber job so that's how you create a
contract using another contract with the
使用另一个带有关键字new的合同的合同，您可以将其中一个发送到
keyword new and you can send either to
the contract you're about to create by
您将要通过使用点值创建合约，然后将
using dot value and then passing in the
amount of ether well that's all I got
以太坊数量，这是我为该视频提供的所有反馈或问题
for this video any feedback or questions
please put them in the comments below or
请把它们放在下面的评论中，或者您可以在此向我发送您的消息
you can send me your message on this
cord where the links are in the
说明中的链接所在的电源线，感谢您收看
descriptions thanks for watching have a
nice week and I'll see you in the next
美好的一周，我会在下一个视频中再见
video